<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="style/uc2html.xsl"?>
<!--
	Example use case
	$Id$
-->
<use-cases xmlns="urn:tu-wien:inso:use-case"
	xmlns:uc="urn:tu-wien:inso:use-case"
	xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

	<title>Reporting - Use Cases</title>

	<xhtml:p>Description in root</xhtml:p>

	<section>
		<title>Reporting</title>

		<xhtml:p>description in Reporting</xhtml:p>

		<uc>
			<title>Log In - Authenticate User</title>
			<desc>
				Authenticate a user by verifying the credentials. Authorization details (roles and permissions) are
				loaded into the user’s identity context, in order to be available for other use cases.
			</desc>
			<actor>User</actor>
			<pre>
				The user is not logged in. No page can be selected by the user prior to this page. If the user accesses
				a page via a direct request to a specific URL, navigation will forward this request to this use case.
			</pre>
			<flow>
				<step>User enters user name and password.</step>
				<step>The combination of user name and password are verified against the identity store.</step>
				<step name="checkpwd">The user name and the hash of the password are found in the identity store.</step>
				<step name="checkexpired">The password for the user account is valid (not expired).</step>
				<step name="checkacct">The user account is enabled.</step>
				<step name="ok">Permissions are loaded into the identity context.</step>
				<step>The user has successfully logged in.</step>
				<alternatives>
					<alternative start="checkpwd">
						<description>User not found</description>
						<step>The user name and the hash of the password could not be found in the identity store.</step>
						<step>User authentication has failed. Use case execution is cancelled.</step>
						<step>User is given the option to continue to reset the user password. <extend ref="uc.user.reset-pwd"/></step>
					</alternative>
					<alternative start="checkexpired" continue="ok">
						<description>User password expired</description>
						<step>The password for the user account has expired.</step>
						<step><include ref="uc.user.set-pwd"/></step>
					</alternative>
					<alternative start="checkacct">
						<description>User account is disabled</description>
						<step>The user account is disabled.</step>
						<step>A message appears, indicating that the user account is disabled.</step>
					</alternative>
				</alternatives>
			</flow>
			<post>
				<extend ref="uc.monitor.list-env"/> Alternatively, the page requested prior to being redirected to the
				login screen is displayed.
			</post>
			<non-funct>Password is echoed, but masked with the system's default password mask (e.g. default: '*').</non-funct>
		</uc>

		<uc xml:id="uc.user.reset-pwd">
			<title>Reset User Password</title>
			<desc>Reset the password for a user account.</desc>
			<actor>User</actor>
			<pre>
				The user is not logged in, and has unsuccessfully tried to log into the application.
			</pre>
			<flow>
				<step>User enters user name and indicates that the password should be reset.</step>
				<step>Confirmation token is generated and valid for 30 minutes (to be confirmed by customer).</step>
				<step>A confirmation email is sent to the user’s mail address that contains a URL to access the confirmation token.</step>
				<step>The user accesses the confirmation token via the URL from the email.</step>
				<step>The user indicates that he wants to reset the password.</step>
				<step><include ref="uc.user.set-pwd"/></step>
			</flow>
			<post>User password has been changed.</post>
		</uc>

	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Monitoring</title>

		<uc xml:id="uc.monitor.list-env">
			<title>List Environments</title>
			<desc>Displays a list of all available environments.</desc>
			<actor>User</actor>
			<pre>None</pre>
			<flow>
				<step>A user logs into the system.</step>
				<step>A list of enabled and disabled environments is displayed, which the user is allowed to view.</step>
			</flow>
			<post>The user can view the details of a specific environment by selecting it.</post>
		</uc>

	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Administration and Permission</title>

		<section>
			<title>Manage Projects</title>
		</section>

		<section>
			<title>Manage Users</title>

			<uc xml:id="uc.user.set-pwd">
				<title>Set User Password</title>
				<desc>Sets the password for a new user, or modifies it for an existing user.</desc>
				<actor>Administrator or User</actor>
				<pre>
					<xhtml:ul>
						<li>	Administrator: an administrator needs to be logged in and a user other than the
						administrator is selected.</li>
						<li>User: a user is logged in and in the process of changing the password for the associated
						user account.</li>
					</xhtml:ul>
				</pre>
				<flow>
					<step>The user password is set to a value indicated by the actor.</step>
					<step name="checkadmin">The actor and the user denote different entities</step>
					<step>The user is assigned a new temporary password that has already expired.</step>
					<step>The user account is updated accordingly.</step>
					<alternatives>
						<alternative start="checkadmin">
							<description>User account represents actor</description>
							<step>The actor and the user denote the same entity</step>
							<step>The user is assigned a new temporary password with an expiry of 90 days.</step>
							<step>The user account is updated accordingly</step>
						</alternative>
					</alternatives>
				</flow>
				<post>The user was modified.</post>
			</uc>
		</section>

	</section>

</use-cases>
